<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A proclamation anent seminary priests, Jesuits and trafficking papists.</title>
            <author>Scotland. Privy Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1698</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B05508</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S1650</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R183375</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52529254</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52529254</idno>
            <idno type="VID">178994</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B05508)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 178994)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2775:65)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A proclamation anent seminary priests, Jesuits and trafficking papists.</title>
                  <author>Scotland. Privy Council.</author>
                  <author>Scotland. Sovereign (1694-1702 : William II)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by the heirs and successors of Andrew Anderson, Printer to the Kings most excellent Majesty,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno Dom. 1698.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Initial letter.</note>
                  <note>Intentional blank spaces in text.</note>
                  <note>Dated: Given under Our Signet at Edinburgh, the fourth day of March, and of Our Reign the ninth year, 1698.</note>
                  <note>Signed: Gilb. Eliot. Cls. Sti. Concilii.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: stained with slight loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Catholic Church --  Clergy --  Legal status, laws, etc. --  Scotland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Jesuits --  Legal status, laws, etc. --  Scotland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Catholics --  Legal status, laws, etc. --  Scotland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="royal_proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:178994:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 9 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:178994:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 9 -->
            <head>A PROCLAMATION<lb/>
               <hi>Anent Seminary Priests, Jeſuits and Trafficking Papists.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <hi>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>ILLIAM</hi> By the Grace of GOD, King of <hi>Great-Britain, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> Defender of the Faith,</signed>
               <salute>To Our Lovits  <gap reason="blank" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈1 span left blank〉</desc>
                  </gap>  Macers of Our Privy Council, Meſſengers at Arms, Our Sheriffs in that part, conjunctly and ſeverally, ſpecially conſtitute, Greeting:</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>Forasmuch as, notwithſtanding the many good and laudable Laws made againſt Seminary Prieſts, Jeſuits, and Trafficking Papiſts, Adverſaries to the true Religion profeſt within this Realm, And particularly the Acts fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing, <hi>viz. Par.</hi> 7. <hi>K. J.</hi> 6. <hi>Cap.</hi> 105. <hi>That no Subjects nor Strangers, Adverſaries to the ſaid true Religion, remain within this Realm, unleſs they obey the Low, anent giving their Confeſſion of Faith. Act Ja.</hi> 6. <hi>Par.</hi> 11. <hi>Cap.</hi> 24. <hi>That any Seminary Priest, when found within this Realm, incur the Pain of Death, and Eſcheat of Moveables; and that the Reſetters and Supplyers of ſuch by the ſpace of three Days and three Nights, tyne their Liferents. Act Ja.</hi> 6. <hi>Par.</hi> 12. <hi>Cap.</hi> 120. <hi>That the Reſetting of Jeſuits, Seminary Priests, and Trafficking Papiſts, againſt the King and the preſent Religion, inſer the Crime and Pain of Treaſon, both against the Perſons Reſet, and their Reſetters. Act Ja.</hi> 6. <hi>Par.</hi> 16. <hi>Cap.</hi> 18. <hi>That all Jeſuits, Semina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Priests, Excommunicat and Trafficking Papiſts, common Enemies to all Chriſtian Government, be apprehended and committed by all Magiſtrats, until they be put out of the Kingdom, or puniſhed conform to the Acts of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; and that none Reſet them, under the Pains therein-expreſt. Act Charl.</hi> 2. <hi>Par.</hi> 1. <hi>Seſſ.</hi> 1. <hi>Cap.</hi> 8. <hi>That all Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuits, Prieſts, and Trafficking Papiſts remove furth of the Kingdom, under the Pain of Death: And Act Charl.</hi> 2. <hi>Par.</hi> 3. <hi>Cap.</hi> 6. <hi>Requiring all Judges and Officers, to put the Laws against Popery and Papiſts, to full and vigorous Execution;</hi> Yet nevertheleſs, ſeveral Popiſh Prieſts, Jeſuits and Trafficking Papiſts, preſume to Reſort within, and Infeſt this Kingdom: Therefore We, with Advice of the Lords of Our Privy Council, have thought fit to Command, and hereby ſtrictly Command and Charge all Sheriffs, Lords of Regality, Stewarts and Baillies, and all their Deputs, and all Magiſtrats of Burghs, Juſtices of Peace, and other Officers of the Law whatſoever, to cauſe Search for, Seek and Apprehend, within their reſpective Bounds, all Jeſuits, Prieſts and Trafficking Papiſts, that ſhall be found within the ſame; and that they imme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diatly cauſe Tranſport them, when apprehended, under ſure Guard from Sheriff to Sheriff, as uſe is, to the Tolbooth of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> where the Magiſtrats of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and Keepers of the ſaid Tolbooth, are to receive and detain them Priſoners, until they be Puniſhed, or Baniſhed conform to the ſaid Act, as Our Privy Council ſhall appoint. And further, We with Advice foreſaid, Command and Charge the ſaid Sheriffs, Magiſtrats, and other Officers of the Law, to take up the Names of all Reſetters of Prieſts, Jeſuits, and Trafficking Papiſts within their Bounds, with their Deſignations, and the Names of ſuch Witneſſes as can give Evidence againſt them: As alſo, that they take up the Names and Deſignations of all Popiſh Pedagogues, School-Maſters and Miſtriſſes within their Bounds, and Tranſmit the ſame to the Clerk of Our Privy Council with all Diligence: Certifying the ſaid Sheriffs, Magiſtrats, and other Officers of the Law, that if they failȝie in the Premiſſes, and to give a Return of their Diligence to the Clerk of Our Privy Council, betwixt and the firſt Day of <hi>June</hi> next to come, they ſhall be Sum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moned to appear, and ſeverely puniſhed according to their Demerit, <hi>O<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>R WILL IS HEREFORE,</hi> and we Charge you ſtraitly and Command, that incontinent theſe Our Letters ſeen, ye paſs to the Mercat Croſs of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and to the remanent Mercat Croſſes of the ſeveral Head Burghs within this Kingdom; and there in Our Name and Authority, by open Proclamation, make Publication hereof, that none pretend Ignorance. And Ordains theſe Preſents to be Printed.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given under Our Signet at <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> 
                  <date>the fourth Day of <hi>March,</hi> and of Our Reign the ninth Year, 1698.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Per Actum Dominorum Secreti Concilii.
<hi>GILB. ELIOT.</hi> Cls. Sti. Concilii. </signed>
               <lb/>
GOD Save the KING.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> Printed by the Heirs and Succeſſors of <hi>Andrew Anderſon,</hi> Printer to the Kings moſt Excellent Majeſty, <hi>Anne DOM.</hi> 1698.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
